{
    "title": "ECVIM General Quiz - Gastrointestinal",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The hormone secretin stimulates production of which of the following:",
            "options": [
                "Glucagon",
                "Gastric acid",
                "Pepsinogen",
                "Pancreatic bicarbonate"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Misoprostol is a synthetic analogue of which of the following prostaglandins?",
            "options": [
                "Prostaglandin E1",
                "Prostaglandin E2",
                "Prostaglandin D1",
                "Prostaglandin F2"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The migrating motor complex within the gastrointestinal tract is triggered by which one of the following:",
            "options": [
                "Nitric oxide",
                "Motilin",
                "Cholecystokinin",
                "Secretin"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Trypsinogen is converted into its active form trypsin by which one of the following enzymes:",
            "options": [
                "Chymotrypsin",
                "Pancreatic lipase",
                "Enterokinase",
                "Pancreatic amylase"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The hormone gastrin stimulates secretion of which of the following:",
            "options": [
                "Glucagon",
                "Cholecystokinin",
                "Serotonin",
                "Bombesin"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the main function of the interstitial cells of Cajal within the gastrointestinal tract?",
            "options": [
                "Active propagation of fast wave activity",
                "Production and secretion of serotonin",
                "Generation of electrical slow wave activity",
                "Production of gamma-delta T-lymphocytes"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The hormone cholecystokinin stimulates secretion of which of the following:",
            "options": [
                "Gastric acid",
                "Pancreatic enzyme",
                "Pancreatic bicarbonate",
                "Insulin"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Bile acid synthesis is an important pathway for catabolism of which one of the following compounds:",
            "options": [
                "Bilirubin",
                "Cholesterol",
                "Glycerol",
                "Chylomicron"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following hormones inhibits secretion of other enteroendocrine peptides?",
            "options": [
                "Somatostatin",
                "Substance P",
                "Bombesin",
                "5-hydroxytryptamine"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Which one of the following is oxidized by the intestinal mucosa and serves as the preferential energy substrate of colonocytes:",
            "options": [
                "Lactate",
                "Acetate",
                "Propionate",
                "Butyrate"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": 3
        }
    ]
}
